Please contact us for any inquiries
turkision@gmail.com
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
Men!
Blaming each other will not make our job
any easier.
The importance of listening to Osman is
obvious.
A governor is killed, the one who was
blamed is a Tent's commander's son.
Remember, there is Byzantine on one side,
Seljuk on the other.
Because of this, I say we establish a
fair court in Söğüt inn tomorrow.
Why in Söğüt, and not Kulucahisar?
Osman committed the majority of the
crimes mentioned in Kulucahisar.
We should be the judges.
What matters isn't trial, it's
finding out what the truth is, Kalonoz.
Besides, will any of the Beys, Tents agree with
the decision you'll make in Kulucahisar?
Alişar Bey is right, Kalonoz.
Osman should stand trial in Söğüt so that
no question goes unanswered.
A court established under the guidance
of our fair judges...
... is the most beneficial for all of us.
We also agree with this.
As long as our relationship with my
deceased friend Yorgopolos...
... which is on the verge of war,
is rebuilt.
Let's not shed blood for the reasons
of insignificance.
Osman is a fugitive now.
You couldn't even keep him in the
cage in your own Tent.
What if he doesn't show up in Söğüt inn?
Then, including the murder of
the governor...
... he will have accepted all of
the offences.
I'm sure Osman Bey will be at the court.
Rest assured.
His own uncle couldn't keep him in
his own hands.
How can you be so sure?
The Turkmens in these lands are like
mad horses, Sofia.
Everyone has a different head collar, but
each head collar is tied to the same pole.
I am that pole itself.
A person in the Turkish Tents with words
more powerful than mine...
... is not yet born.
If Osman doesn't come alive...
... his corpse will.
This is the word of the Banner Lord
Alişar Bey.
Since you are this confident in
your words, as allies...
... our part is to trust your word.
We'll be waiting for the news, Alişar Bey.
The truth will come to light tomorrow.
Let's hope for the best for all of us.
Who are they, my Osman?
No need, Bamsı Bey.
- Where is Edebali?
- He sent me.
- My name is Zülfikar.
- We shall go to him swiftly.
- Bamsı Bey, you take the lead here.
- Thank you, Osman. Thank you.
Alişar Bey is giving a helping
hand, you saw it.
He isn't holding Osman at arm's length,
that's why he's moving the court to Söğüt.
Alişar Bey is preparing the wolf's
dining table, my nephew.
He wants those who are out of
breath to die.
It's true that he is giving a helping
hand. But...
... we'll find it out together whether if
this hand will help us or strangle us.
What if the court's decision is
against Osman, uncle?
- Will we sacrifice my brother?
- We need to find Osman first.
We need to submit evidence which will
convince the court that Osman is innocent.
Then I will make him pay for what
he did to Batur.
Osman is my blood, my life.
Only I can punish him.
I hope nothing's wrong.
Osman's Alps. (Men)
So you're here.
Boğaç brother, take Tursun to the
nursing tent.
Very well, brother.
And we'll take Bala Hatun to
Ertuğrul Bey's pavilion, come on!
They are injured, uncle.
Boran Alp!
All rivers fall into the sea.
We're not here to stay, Dündar Bey.
I decide who stays and who leaves
in this Tent.
Who is this Hatun?
Sheikh Edebali's daughter Bala Hatun.
The Hatun who was kidnapped from
the bazaar was Edebali's daughter?
That's right.
Having her as a guest is my Bey's order.
Why did your Bey send the Hatun with you?
Was he not brave enough?
My Bey's bravery can neither be contained
in this Tent nor in these lands.
It's against Kayı laws to make a Muslim
woman in need of help wait.
We'd wreck the whole world for
a drop of Muslim blood.
Tell Zöhre Hatun to take care of
her quickly.
Edebali's daughter is also our daughter.
Come on, take her.
- Peace be with you.
- Peace be with you too.
Zülfikar Dervish told us that you were
aware of the situation.
Bala Hatun is on the verge of death.
What are you looking for here?
Batur, take Osman's Alps to the cage.
Don't let them go anywhere until
Osman comes here.
Dündar Bey, you're stoking the fire.
The fire is not yet ignited Boran Alp.
It's not yet ignited.
Your wish is my command, my Bey.
At last, we have a valuable clay.
It was worth it after all, huh Zülfikar?
Thanks to you, master.
It's not the time to dig around Edebali.
We don't have time.
It's not easy, son. It's not easy.
Neither finding nor existing.
It's not easy.
Making a pot of mystery isn't easy, son.
First, labour. Then patience.
First, light from your eyes, then sweat
from your forehead.
First you get some mud.
Then you seperate the clay from the rock.
Stronger the clay, more durable the pot.
Bala Hatun is fighting for her life in
the Tent.
For this reason, its story is
similar to a human's.
Just like how a pot of mystery
is made from dirt...
... humans were created from dirt.
If its master is capable, and its
core is beautiful...
Both can be shaped easily.
Humans are also like this, Osman Bey.
They're raw, they burn, they cook.
If it's clay is defective, effort is
low, and the fire is small...
The pot of mystery cracks.
Water begins to leak
Just like how Adam was raw.
Fire makes dirt a pot, patience makes
a human mature, son.
A pot of mystery or a human.
What's the difference?
For this reason, if my daughter Bala faces
such hardships...
... overcomes such challenges, stands
against such difficulties...
... then she is the rewarded one.
She is the winner.
So what, just because she was Edebali's
daughter, she wouldn't be tested?
In doomsday, the day in which no one
can help one another...
... what would we do, my little Osman?
Didn't our prophet say, "I won't be
able to help my daughter Fatma that day."?
She has a low pulse.
She is poisoned. We can't do anything.
She will die.
Osman trusted me with her.
This is Hayma Ana's pavilion. You don't
reject someone in need of healing here.
Let's boil some castor oil. We need to
make her puke.
Boil castor oil.
Give me a rag.
Now little Osman. Tell me what's
bothering you.
They wanted to make you pay.
They want the treasure.
If you don't give it to them...
... your daughter Bala...
... will shortly die.
Sons of the devil.
They still think death comes
from the poison.
This arrogance of the little devils...
This devil didn't submit to Adam either.
As long as Allah doesn't allow for it, so
what if they make her drink thousands...
... of poisons, so what if my child dies?
We'll be happy that she'll be our
prophet's neighbour in the afterlife.
You're right.
The ones who don't know about sacrifices,
the ones who can't say goodbye...
... who can't accept being a mortal,
shall not desire anything.
Is it easy to stand before Allah as
a Muslim, little Osman?
A Muslim must be honourable.
Honourable ones are those who don't forget
the truth at the times of hardships.
So are we going to stay here and
do nothing?
- Sofia is Yannis' daughter.
- Yannis' daughter?
Let's see what Yannis will do
when you capture her.
Me capturing Sofia, how do you know these?
We spent our lives digging the proper
clay from the dirt, son.
Our eyes can see a proper man.
Now I'll go to your Tent as a guest.
If you bring the antitoxin, good.
If you can't, don't you blame yourself.
Our cause is having the consciousness
of an ant.
We just want where we stand to be known.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim
(In the name of Allah, the compassionate, the merciful)
You're right, Edebali. What is so
important about this treasure?
It's a piece of wood, son.
A piece of wood.
I'd like to hear about it one day.
- I need to go now.
- Always be on the right path, son.
I bid you farewell.
- Aslı and Kerem.
- I worked hard on it. It's finally done.
Open your eyes, Aygül.
Her corpse is in the pavilion.
Think about where her soul is.
Look what's written here, Sofia.
A verse from the Surah Al-Hujurat
in Quran.
"The believers are but brothers".
Surah Al-Hujurat [49:10]
Quran calls them for unity
and solidarity 82 times.
This is our starting point, Sofia.
A great fire of disorder to be ignited.
Now I'm listening to you. What news did
you bring from the Kayı Tent?
Kayı Tent is boiling, master.
Dündar is very angry towards Osman.
We can use that anger.
Because Osman ignores Dündar as a Bey.
Dündar might be a Bey.
But in Kayı Tent...
... Ertuğrul's son Osman's soul
is wandering about.
I can feel it, Sofia.
Now only for us, Osman will also
cause trouble for Dündar.
This fire we worked up, will take us
to the treasure.
Do you think Osman knows
where the treasure is?
It's impossible for Osman to know where
the treasure is.
Edebali won't ever tell Ahis' secrets
to Osman.
He's so in love with that girl that he'd
oppose even Edebali.
You'll see. He'll bring us the treasure.
Master Yannis. There are news
from Nizamettin.
- Tell me, Helen.
- Osman has sent Bala Hatun to Kayı Tent.
Love.
I bow to you one more time.
I witnessed love's power when
I killed the governor.
But Osman...
We can't be sure what he'll do.
You can be sure that he'll bring
Ahis' treasure, Kalonoz.
The love in him, his hatred toward me...
... will bring me the treasure
sooner or later.
And when he comes, we will
have taken our precautions.
Alişar Bey.
Do you know what the fish and humans have
in common, Nizamettin?
Both get in trouble if they open
their mouth unnecessarily.
Now, spill the beans.
My Bey, it's my greatest honour to be your
eyes and ears, you know that.
- I couldn't keep it, I brought it to you.
- I don't like empty words.
Don't sugarcoat it, tell me quickly!
Sheikh Edebali's daughter Bala Hatun
was poisoned.
They took her to Kayı Tent.
What are they up to?
My Bey, more importantly, Osman is with
Sergeant Samsa.
Most probably Sheikh Edebali is also
with them.
So Edebali is the one who fans
Osman's flame.
We shall put that fire out so that our
words are not in vain.
Now go find Osman. Tell him, Alişar Bey
is calling you to the court.
What if he doesn't want to come, my Bey?
He will. He promised me.
If he doesn't come, I'll rip
his heart out.
I'll blunt that sword of his.
Osman is on fire, my Bey.
What if he does something to Nizamettin?
To feed the fish, you have to
sacrifice the bread, Zorba.
My father...
... took your Alp status. If it was me,
I would have taken your lives.
If you were a fire, you'd burn a
place of your size, Batur.
For Osman Bey's cause, we are honoured if
our Alp status is taken...
... or our lives are taken.
It will be your Bey Osman's
turn eventually.
If you're any brave untie my hands.
- Untie them!
- I will.
I will but first, you all will see
what punishment is!
You all will see what punishment is!
You all will see!
Every single one of you will know what
a punishment is!
So, we kissed your hand, we split your
bread with our own hands.
Won't you help yourself, Konur brother?
We kissed each other's hands, we took
the edge off...
From now on even the grass we step on
will heal us.
- Yes, Sergeant Samsa.
- Thank you.
Such trees rumble with their leaves.
- Wonderful, wonderful!
- May we come in, Osman Bey?
Come in, Çetin Alp.
My Bey, ruler of the New Bazaar
Nizamettin is here.
He has something to tell you if you
please.
Let him come in. Let's see what he wants.
They are looking for me everywhere.
Where did you hear about it Nizamettin?
As you know Osman Bey, knowledge
is more valuable than coin.
You must have eyes and ears everywhere,
so that you can know.
Keep your eyes open. You might be
blinded one day.
You might go deaf.
Shall I cut his ears and put his eyes out
so he can no longer work, Osman Bey?
Let him go, Sergeant Samsa.
Tell me. What brings you here?
Alişar Bey wants you to come up to court
and stand trial.
He wants it so the real killers can
come to light.
He wants it so you can go hunting
together like in the old days.
Say hello to Alişar Bey for us.
He shall feel at ease.
Everything will come to light tomorrow.
Hatun. What's the state of Bala Hatun?
It's not good, Gündüz Bey.
They poisoned her.
If we can't find a cure, I don't know
if she will see another day.
- May I come in, my Bey?
- Come in, Kılıç Alp.
My Bey, Sheikh Edebali is here.
Don't make him wait, let him come in.
- Peace be with you.
- Peace be with you too.
You have honoured Ertuğrul Gazi's
pavilion, Edebali. Welcome.
Thank you.
We're welcomed, son. Is Bala Hatun inside?
Gonca Hatun is with her. She is resting.
If you allow me, I want to see
my daughter.
Not at all!
Osman stepped on our laws, he stepped
on you.
Give Osman the punishment he deserves.
Osman not only threatens your
prosperity, your pavilion, our son...
... but also Aygül.
What are you trying to say, Hatun?
My Bey... Aygül is in love with
Osman, my Bey.
Osman doesn't feel anything towards Aygül.
We need to take precautions before Aygül
works herself up.
How?
A proper marriage will bring
us and Aygül peace.
What are you trying to say, Hatun?
Who do you have in mind?
Alişar Bey.
Alişar Bey's Hatun passed away last year.
I say we marry Alişar Bey to Aygül.
When he came to the tent with
Sofia and Kalanoz today...
I saw how Alişar Bey looked at Aygül.
We should meet Alişar Bey
as soon as possible...
and tell him about it.
- Aygül...
- Can I come in, my Bey?
Come in.
What are you doing at this time of the night?
My Bey...
Sheikh Edebalı is in our tent.
You should...
have your eyes on him.
- I'll know everything he does.
- Okay, my Bey.
What will we do, my Bey?
Edebalı is...
trouble.
It means that we'll take on...
Mongols' rage and Seljuqs' doubt.
I'm afraid that there's a connection...
- between Osman and Edebalı.
- Won't you say something to him?
No need to rush.
Let him embrace his daughter.
Let him settle.
Don't forget...
the hunt leaves a trace...
and the hunter...
traces.
Our Mother Hacer was desperate too...
because...
the water that Prophet
İbrahim left to them...
was run short.
Our Mother Hacer who
worried about her son İsmail...
dying of thirst in Mecca....
started to seek for water...
between Safa and Marwa.
When she went for seven times...
her son İsmail was exhausted.
Thirst shook his little body.
With the wisdom of Allah...
she clicked his heels.
Our Mother heard a voice then.
She looked behind and saw that in the
place she left İsmail...
there was water.
Cebrail (a.s) created a water resource...
after he saw the trouble...
İsmal and Mother Hacer had been
going through...
with the permission of Allah.
They named it Zemzem.
- It is healthy for Muslims, in sha Allah.
- In sha Allah.
This will keep my daughter strong until
the cure arrives, in sha Allah.
I wish Osman had never grown up.
I wish he had been still a kid...
not moving anywhere,
staying with you.
Among all those troubles...
being silent just to keep the tent safe...
Annoys me, Hatun (lady).
My Gündüz.
My Man.
Everyone in the tent knows that you
are fair.
Don't worry.
This is Osman.
He has always been zippy.
Also, you know that he is brave.
He can take care of himself.
Don't worry.
No, Hatun. No.
This time it is different.
He is in great trouble.
I fear that something bad will happen
to him.
If he doesn't appear in the court tomorrow,
it means he accepts the provision.
Everyone is tearing into him.
You won't leave Osman alone, will you?
Never.
Even if he causes trouble...
he is still my brother.
My wolf-eyed brother.
He is entrusted to me by my parents.
Then...
you need to take care of him.
I took precautions.
If something goes wrong...
I'll abduct Osman.
My uncle doesn't know.
I can't let anyone get him.
No one.
People go away.
Family stays.
Family is permanent.
This is what Gündüz Bey, the
grandchild of Süleyman Shah...
Shah and son of Ertğrul Ghazi should do.
May Allah open our way, my man.
Amin, Hatun.
Aybars!
In sha Allah, I will take revenge for you,
my brother.
What is happening here?
Get out!
Clumsy men!
Why are you tiring yourself up, Princess?
We need to be prepared for everything,
Commander.
Did you take all the precautions?
Don't worry, darling.
Everything is okay, but...
I don't understand.
Why is this treasure so important?
Let us kill all the Ahis and Kayıs.
We should finish this matter.
If it was that easy...
We would have finished it, Kalanoz.
What is the hard thing here, Sofia?
We have a strong army.
Byzantine supports us.
We just need to declare a war.
Those Turks...
can't get on well with each other.
But when someone from outside attacks
them...
They stand together
and turn into a dragon.
It was always like that, and this
will go on like that.
But, don't worry.
Master Yannis' intelligence make us...
superior against them.
I can't wait to capture Osman, but...
This is Osman.
Alişer Bey is involved too.
Osman has to obey him.
If he doesn't come, it will mean that
he accepts the provision.
In that case, Alişar Bey will find him
before we do.
The time has come.
Let's go and get Osman.
"I seek refuge in Allah from accursed Shaitan"
"In the name of God, the Most
Gracious, the Most Merciful"
By the racers, panting,
"And the producers of sparks [when] striking
And the chargers at dawn,"
"Stirring up thereby [clouds of] dust,
Arriving thereby in the center collectively,
Indeed mankind, to his Lord, is ungrateful.
And indeed, he is to that a witness.
And indeed he is, in love of wealth, intense.
But does he not know that when the contents of the graves are scattered
And that within the breasts is obtained,
Indeed, their Lord with them,
that Day, is [fully] Acquainted.
"Allaah Almighty has spoken the truth"
Recitator: İsmail Hakkı Ürün
Aka Samsa Çavuş
My Bey, why are you tying the tail of
the horse?
So that it can know.
- So that it can know.
- Know what, my Bey?
That this is a war and this tie will break
if there is death in the end.
This is a tradition, son.
We tie the tail of the horse so that
it can know that there is a war.
If its owner is martyred...
its tail is cut and be used as a plume.
Eyvallah (thank you) my Bey.
Ya Allah!
This weapon is my brother Aybars'.
If I can't take revenge for my brother
with this weapon today...
May it stick into my heart.
The shahada (martyrdom) day has come,
brothers!
Today, we will send the enemy to hell!
- Allah is the greatest!
- Protect Princess Sofia!
- Protect her!
They are here.
I was waiting you to see at the court,
Osman Bey.
I decided to establish divine justice
here, Sofia.
I guess I will be the judge of that court.
Hunting time!
He trapepd us!
Bala Hatun will be killed because of you,
Osman Bey.
Alps!
From now on...
I am the one to decide here!
- Allah is eternal!
I want Osman Alive!
With our own Kadıs (Muslim Judge), we
set up a fair court, Dündar Bey.
Whatever the consequences are, we'll
substitute the peace in Söğüt again.
The peace that my brother
Ertuğrul Bey left when he went..
was spoiled by Osman.
Today, every problem
should be solved here.
We'll reach the
freedom together, Alişar Bey.
Don't worry, Dündar Bey. Let's go.
Kadıs(muslim judge) are about to come.
Deploy behind the Han. If something
goes wrong...
we'll take Osman.
Kılıçalp...
Even if he's my uncle, I
won't give him Osman.
Osman...
You're entrusted to me by my mother.
I won't let anyone take you.
You'll die today!
Inglorious.
You'll get in trouble, Osman.
With a word that came out
of your ominous mouth...
you killed my son.
The death will be haram
(bad for Islam) for me...
if I don't cut your cruel tongue.
I know about...
every sword blow that cut
your son's body, Bamsı Bey.
His death was as heavy as his pain.
Don't, Bamsı Bey!
Bamsı...
Bamsı Bey...
You'll go to the court, Andreas.
Tell everyone what I've done.
Tell them that I didn't run
away from the court.
Osman took Governor's murderer Sofia.
From Alparslan...
your 200 years-long curse is over.
Osman Bey...
In these lands...
you won't even have your graves.
We pray Fatihah after our martyrs.
No one will remember you.
You ordered your dogs to kill Aybars.
I won't let you martyr Bala Hatun.
Now...
go and tell Yannis that...
if he wants his daughter Sofia...
he should bring me
the cure for Bala Hatun.
Or...
I'll kill his daughter.
I'll wait for you in the tent.
If you don't come...
I'll kill Sofia.
You can't do it.
No, Kalanoz!
We can't let Turks win!
Don't go.
Don't go!
Kalanoz, don't go! Kalanoz!
Don't go, Kalanoz!
Kalanoz!
Don't go!
The poison is working.
That's why she sweats, sir.
It's a earthly poison in her blood.
If Allah permits, we'll find a cure.
- She will recover in sha Allah.
- In sha Allah, sir.
However, there are such poisons that...
they capture one's soul.
And they don't vanish until killing
the heart.
For example, jealousy.
For example, grudge.
Resurullah s.a.v (Prophet Muhammed) was
asked...
who is the best person.
He replied that anyone who tells the truth
and...
clean-hearted.
People were surprised.
They said: " Resulullah (Prophet Muhammed)
"We know about being hones...
but what is clean-hearted?"
Our Master eyed everyone and told...
that "that is a clean heart which
fears from Allah...
It is sinless...
and it has no feelings like cruelty and
grudge."
This is Kalanoz's man.
What is happening?
- Where is princess Sofia?
- Osman.
He took Osman.
He sent me to inform you.
Ah, my brother, this is not going to
end well.
Osman!
Osman disobeyed me.
He disobeyed the state!
The state will disobey you, too!
Groom! Get my horse ready!
Gündüz Bey, gather your Alps.
We are going to find Osman.
Farabi...
scholars like you...
Warriors like Osman...
I wish they had been in my religion.
Then God's kingdom would rule in this
world.
Commander Kalanoz.
What happened to you, Kalanoz?
Osman...
He took Sofia.
He wants Bala Hatun's life in return of
Sofia's life.
- Where?
- In the dark valley.
Osman...
Damn you and your family!
Is Sofia your daughter?
Only Edebali could know this.
This is why they abducted.
So, that is the truth.
Sofia is your daughter.
How can Edebali know a secret
that you hide from everyone?
There is no secret any longer.
Now, there is only death.
Now, listen to me very carefully.
My Sheikh.
Allah is the healer.
Allah gives us hope.
- Allah is the healer.
- Fa....ther...
- Allah Gives us hope
- You'll be fine Bala.
- Allah is the healer.
- Hold on.
Allah gives us hope.
Allah is the healer.
Bismillah.
(in the name of God, the merciful and compassionate.)
- My Allah, give her strength.
- Allah is the healer.
Bismillah.
(in the name of God, the merciful and compassionate.)
Allah is the healer.
Allah gives us hope.
Sergeant Samsa.
Keep an eye on Sofia.
Osman!
You will meet your match!
You'll pay for your sins!
Can I come in?
Yes, son.
- Peace be with you.
- I'll break your nose, don't push me.
- Sofia!
Today, we will call you to account.
We will take revenge for my Aybars.
Osman fooled you all.
He did this to escape from the court.
Wake up!
You and your tent will
pay for his sins, too.
Get your hands off.
How is her situation, Aunt Ayşe?
- Not good, Osman.
- She'll be fine, in sha Allah, Aunt Ayşe.
- She will be fine.
- In sha Allah.
- Princess Sofia.
- Alişer Bey.
What is happening? Osman abducted me.
He killed my soldiers!
What does this mean, Bamsı Bey?
Release princess Sofia immediately.
Osman!
Where are you?
Are you looking for me, Alişar Bey?
Ertuğrul Ghazi's son Osman.
He doesn't run from justice.
Haven't you realised this yet?
Deal with Osman, or we will declare war
against you, Alişar Bey.
Haven't you realised this yet?
Deal with Osman, or we will declare war
against you, Alişar Bey.
Soldiers!
Arrest Osman Bey!
Do you disobey the state?
Why don't you trust me, Alişar Bey?
I told you that there would be a
fair court.
I kept my word.
You can't judge me.
You can judge Sofia.
Osman!
Justice will prevail here, in my father's
tent.
Now, you should hear the truth from
me, Alişar Bey.
I kept my word.
The potion is here, Osman Bey.
This will heal Bala.
Thank Allah.
Help me, daughter.
Let her drink this.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
(In the name of Allah, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful.)
My Allah...
you are the healer.
You are the most merciful.
You are the hope.
O Healer (Allah)
- O Healer (Allah)
This weapon belongs to my brother
Aybars, who is a martyr.
I have had the honor of this weapon
so far.
I trust you, and I am giving this weapon's
honor to you, Alişar Bey.
Is Osman Bey telling the truth, Kalanoz?
So, you attacked the market.
Not us. Monk Yannis, who is the murderer
of our governor, did it.
Are you insane, Kalanoz?
Master Yannis is a holy man.
How can you say this?
This is an internal matter.
This is not right.
Three of you were involved.
We are retracting all the accusations
on Osman Bey.
I took Bala's cure,
then imprisoned Yannis.
I will question him tonight and
execute him tomorrow.
Lie!
You are lying!
All of you are my son's murderers.
Yannis killed your son, Aybars.
I am sorry for that.
I invite all of you to
tomorrow's execution.
You will witness Yannis' death.
Princess Sofia is innocent.
If you don't want war, I want you
to release her.
- I won't let this happen!
- Osman, enough.
The murderer of Aybars and the guilty of
the market attack has been found.
Thanks to Kalanoz, Bala Hatun
will be good.
Osman, what do you want?
Justice!
I will not stop until there is justice!
I will maintain the agreement of peace and
trade in the name of Governor Yorgopolos.
Let's drop the subject here, Alişar Bey.
Otherwise, we will lose people
in these lands.
Allah is the healer.
- O Healer (Allah).
- O Healer (Allah)
O Healer (Allah)
Father.
Daughter.
- Gonca.
- Bala.
Thank you my Allah.
Thank you.
Thank Allah.
You're free to go, Kalanoz!
I don't want hostility anymore.
Or you'll pay for it.
Commander!
Take Princess Sofia and Commander
Kalanoz to the castle.
If something happens to
them, I'll kill all of you!
Your command, my Bey.
I won't let my son's murderer
go freely from this tent.
Osman.
Osman. Enough!
You pit the Seljuqs against our tent.
I'll keep an eye on both of you, Kalanoz.
It's not over for me.
Bamsı Bey...
we'll go to witness
Yannis' execution tomorrow.
When Yannis dies tomorrow...
you'll understand that I'm right.
My God, why did you leave me alone?
I've worked for your kingdom all my life.
Forgive me.
I couldn't let anyone get Sofia.
Put out the fire in my heart.
Save my soul from this pain.
I beg you to forgive my sins...
and faults, my God.
My God, help us.
Take pity on us and protect us.
Hold on a little, my Tursun.
It'll sooth soon.
You'll get better.
The wounds on my breast hurt less than...
the ones on my heart.
What's on your heart? Tell me.
We look at the sky, it' far away.
We look at the ground, it's hard.
How will we get out of this situation?
The bazaar was raided...
and our friend Gonca died.
These unbelievers...
try your patience.
The one who can make the
ground bed and...
the sky blanket will
show us a way out.
Rest, Tursun.
Okay, my Sheikh...
Okay.
Our stalls were ruined.
And our goods.
It'll take a long time for us to recover.
What did Dervish Yunus say?
"Each moment we get born anew...
No one could grow weary
of us." - Yunus Emre
The old man that you gave
a present at the bazaar is
Yannis who dressed up like a dervish.
Prophet's people came.
They did.
They became the sign of end time.
Our nature gets fulled with death.
It does.
Many problems exist, friends.
Your handicraft...
I didn't want to leave it.
I thought about their love and...
I found solace in it.
Even if I die like Aslı...
I'll be fine.
You're in my life.
I won't let you go, Bala Hatun.
As you say.
Ask for me in marriage, from my father.
If you let me...
then...
when my father returns, I'll do it.
Excuse me.
Can I come in, Osman Bey?
Come in, Konur.
What happened? Tell me.
What's it?
Dündar Bey...
He not only caged our Alps (men)...
but he also took their weapons.
It's time to settle accounts
with Dündar Bey.
So that we get rid of the troubles...
we better clear up the tent.
We haven't talked about the trade issue
for a long time.
The new bazaar is recovering.
We need to...
manufacture something in the carpet room.
Don't worry about it, Dündar Bey.
Kayı's Hatuns (ladies) will do it.
When the new bazaar recovers...
Kayıs' goods will be the best-qualified
ones.
- Elhamdülillah (Thanks Allah).
- Thank Allah.
We got rid all of our problems.
From now on, it is about our
passion.
No, nephew. No.
We didn't get rid all of our problems.
I have an issue with Osman.
This has gone beyond too much.
I have no intention to lose this tent
because of Osman's immaturity, Gündüz.
I really wonder, there has been a lot of
things.
Hasn't he got something to tell his uncle
as an explanation?
Not just an explanation!
I also need to call you to account,
Dündar Bey!
You caged my alps (men).
I can explain this, Osman.
But you need to explain my Batur's
situation
I had an issue with Batur.
I solved it.
Now, free my alps.
- Otherwise...
- Otherwise what, Osman?
I will solve my problem with Batur
entirely.
Uncle, you heard Kalanoz.
Osman has been proved to right.
- We need to free the alps.
- Gündüz.
Do not interfere.
He is chasing revenge for Aybars!
However, my son's blood is still fresh!
Your son has paid his treason.
Osman, Uncle!
Enough!
Enough already!
Osman. Look.
Your brother is on your side.
Gündüz was involved in that, too.
So, will you betray us?
Blood for blood.
Don't you know that?
Uncle!
If you want blood...
here you go.
I knew you weren't going to betray me,
Kalanoz.
There was no other way to save you,
Sofia.
So, it was a game.
We have grand ideas that tie us together.
Not just our ideals.
Did you request for this execution?
Yes, my daughter.
I'll die.
I need to be executed in front of Osman
and others' eyes.
I will never let this happen.
They need to kill me first.
The first thing that they taught us in the
Margarıt Abbey was that...
You can't live without dying, Sofia.
- Osman.
- How can you do this to yourself, Osman?
Why are you so sad, Aygül?
Haven't you seen Osman, mother?
He stabbed himself!
Don't you have honor?
You are Dündar Bey's daughter, Aygül Hatun.
Why are you crying?
Pull yourself together!
-Mother...
-If you go on crying, don't call me mother again.
Mother, what are you talking about?
I...
You are crying for Osman, who
killed your brother...
and disobeyed your father, your Bey.
You are crying for Osman!
Get out of this tent and you'll see.
He organised everybody.
He is rebelling against his uncle.
And you cry for him, ha?
- Mother, look...
- Shut up!
You should be ashamed of yourself
as a Kayı.
Look, daughter. You need to marry a
strong Bey.
You'll marry a strong Bey and make
your father stronger.
I am not talking about a random Bey
or his son, I mean the Bannerlord.
- You'll marry Alişar Bey, Aygül.
- Mother, I prefer dying.
- I prefer dying, mother!
- That's all I have to say, Aygül.
You shall not speak.
If you don't do what I say, you are
dead to me.
Osman has proved his braveness, father.
Yes, my Sheikh. If it wasn't for him,
neither Bala Hatun nor Tursun would live.
The one who puts braveness and faith
into hearts...
is Allah.
As to Osman...
he is a rookie for now.
If he is disciplined well...
and trained well, he will be a
sharp sword.
If not...
he will be just a piece of iron.
Osman.
Osman Bey, what happened to you?
I punished myself.
Don't worry, Edebali.
Did you stab yourself?
The dagger fastened on my body.
However, the blood is Dündar Bey's.
Remember that...
Wounds can heal.
But the grudge doesn't go away.
Rest here.
- I will go to the Alp Tent.
- Eyvallah (okay) Osman Bey.
Eyvallah (okay).
Drain the blood.
I'll set up a fire.
We need to brand the wound.
May peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you, too.
Boran, son.
Son, what happened?
It's nothing important, Bamsı Bey.
If there's nothing important, then
what are those scars, brother Boran?
Who did this to you?
Batur came here, Konuralp,
then this happened.
How quickly did Batur
forget about his knife wound!
I will deal with him now.
Samsa Bey, don't let what
happened here be heard outside.
Osman Bey is busy with his own troubles,
don't let us trouble him too.
Sergeant Samsa, Boran Alp is right.
Now is not the right time.
If not today, then tomorrow...
... if not tomorrow, then later.
Spilled blood won't go without
punishment, brother Boran.
You will not get away with this Batur.
You will not get away with this.
Today, we have lost blood.
But when the time comes,
we will spill their blood.
Thank you, brother.
Thank you.
My Osman, my brother.
When will you stop bleeding?
Look at you.
There is more blood
to be spilled, brother.
There is more blood to be spilled.
"In the name of God, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful"
Like you said, brother...
Valiants take matters
into their own hands.
"In the name of God, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful"
Erkut Alp.
You should go take a look and
find out where Osman Bey is.
Yes, my Bey.
Erkut Alp is two feet tall.
One foot is just stomach.
You say two feet tall, brother Konur,
but there's more than that.
I know, brother Boran, I know. When I say
two feet, another one is just his heart.
You are right.
When we arrived at the Tent, you gave your
hide to Osman Bey, and your tent to me.
Now, you are my guest in my tent, I won't let
you go anywhere tonight, Sergeant Samsa.
Thank you, Konur Alp, I'm not
intending to go anywhere either.
Mashallah, valiants.
What is it, Erkut, were you scared
because we might eat your share too?
What is it?
Okay, you should sit.
What is it, Bamsı Bey?
Sons, my Osman is
apparently busy right now.
But cancelling a table is against
the traditions of valiants.
So, let's start then, come on.
Come on, Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
- Here, son.
- Thank you, my Bey. Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Would a daughter of Bey
cry like this, Aygül Hatun?
I'm not with Osman while he is bleeding.
Then go! Go to his side!
He spilled your brother's blood.
He will also drain your tears, go!
Burçin, that's enough,
don't be so hard on me!
That's enough, I'm begging you!
Your eyes are blind except to Osman,
but Osman's eyes can only see Bala.
I have never loved anyone
but Osman in my life, Burçin.
Then what, Aygül, have you ever
heard any good words in your life?
Have you ever seen a smile, tell me, was
it worth the tears you've dropped for him?
Was it worth it, Aygül?
My Allah...
... give me the strength to be patient.
Or just take my life, I'm begging you.
Take it so I will be relieved.
Osman Bey.
You honored us, welcomed
us in your father's Tent.
If Gündüz Bey allows me to, I would
want to speak a few words to you.
Friends informed me, you cut
someone's hand in the bazaar.
- It was a thief.
- Now you've hurt yourself.
- I punished myself.
- Are you the justice, Osman Bey?
If that's necessary, then I am!
Do you really think...
... justice is secured by brute
force and a black weapon?
What can overcome injustice
but a black weapon, Edebali?
Justice can.
Justice needs the ability to see
a white hair in white milk...
... and the ability to see a
black snake on a black rock.
Justice does not only needs a strong
arm and a black weapon...
... it also needs foresight, and insight.
His holiness, Usame once killed a man who recited
the kalima shahadah and asked for mercy.
Our Prophet called Usame.
He said, "Did you kill a man who
has announced his faith?"
When Usame defended himself by saying
"He said the words because he was scared."...
Our benevolent Prophet said...
" Did you open his heart out to speak
so sure about his intentions, his feelings?"
Osman Bey.
Is it right to do as you please...
... without even asking, consulting...
... thinking thoroughly about
it, even if it was a thief?
Where is the kadi?
Where are the witnesses?
Where is the trial?
You judge by yourself,
and decide by yourself.
And we are not skilled enough
to read people's hearts.
If we have a talent like this, then we
should first read our own hearts.
Now, let's talk about your bleeding wound.
While Our Prophet Muhammad,
Sallallahu Alaihi Wasallam (PBUH) even warned...
... Ebu'd- Derda, who was harming
his body by keeping himself...
... from all the world's
flavours by saying...
... " Your soul is your
wrist, treat it well."...
... would it be right to harm
yourself, stab yourself?
Osman, blazing like a flash in the pan.
Little Osman.
We say " When you walk,
let the justice walk with you...
..." when you smile, let the
mercy smile with you...
..." when you endure tyranny,
let the patience stand up for you...
..." and let the people see
the government in you."
But look at what you do.
Naive Osman, little Osman.
A swift person hardly ever
gets a job done right.
You should know it like this.
Son, Boran. A horse has strong feet,
a bard has an agile tongue.
May neither our adhans nor our bards be
silenced. Come on, sing a song for us.
A bard with a dombra has words,
a Bey has his commands.
Will it be a mournful or a
cheerful one, my Bamsı Bey?
Son, it should neither be
a mournful, or a cheerful one.
May it has wisdom. May it has wisdom, son.
My Ertuğrul Bey loved how you sing
"Sevda-yı Muhammed".
- Sing us that.
- Thank you, my Bey.
Then let's be with the Great Yesevi,
the sage of Turkistan.
Yes, yes, let us be with him so that our
hearts can be filled with his wisdom, son.
Thank you.
"Sevda-yı Muhammed", from Hoca Ahmet Yesevi
Love of Muhammed happened to me.
That is why I am devoted to Muhammed.
One with an ummah is always grateful.
Then, my Allah, let me
be a devotee of Muhammed.
Allah gave me the love of Muhammed.
Let me be a devotee of just Muhammed.
Love of Muhammed happened to me.
That is why I am devoted to Muhammed.
Making me go through the
whole universe like Mecnun.
Making me go crazy for Muhammed.
He's never eaten food, but always sorrow.
You are the miracle of Muhammed's sorrow.
Love of Muhammed happened to me.
That is why I am devoted to Muhammed.
Shah of shahs asked for ummah's sins.
There is no fear in us in the
judgment day because of Muhammed.
Let me fly away with your grace, Allah.
Give me a drop of Muhammed's sea.
Love of Muhammed happened to me.
That is why I am devoted to Muhammed.
Let your dark face meet Pir-i Kamil's feet.
If He pleases, he would
allow us to see Muhammed.
This poor Yesevi wants to
see The Holy Chamber.
Would it be possible to
reach his feet's dirt?
Love of Muhammed happened to me.
That is why I am devoted to Muhammed.
- MashAllah, my valiant.
- Thank you, my Bey.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
My Allah...
... our love, fight or even intentions...
... are of Muhammed(saw)'s.
He is the warrior we
obey from all eternity.
We go to the battlefields with his name,
and be victorious with his name.
My Allah, we forged
His name on our hearts...
We forged His name on our efforts,
we forged His name on our eyes.
My Allah, don't let our
efforts be without His wish.
Amin.
My Allah, if we are hungry, we will
be satiated with His name.
If we are naked, we will
put on his love for us.
If we die, we will live with his cause.
My Allah, he is our beloved.
The blood we spill is for him...
... the glory we take, the reputation
we have, all of these are for him.
My Allah, don't let us and our
descendants stray from his way.
Amin.
Because friends of Ertuğrul
Gazi can't be without him.
They would give their lives,
but not their beloved.
I will marry you when
my father comes back.
Welcome, Aygül Hatun.
This is my uncle's Tent, you came here,
but you are not welcome here, you should know that.
Many of your friends died in the bazaar but you
are looking at a plate and smiling, Hatun.
Tell me.
What is the secret you are keeping?
Our friends died, may Allah
have mercy on their souls.
But you know, I also barely saved my life.
Ever since you came to our Tent,
we are cursed with troubles.
I know very well that death
is walking with you, Hatun.
One who says "I know.",
doesn't know anything.
And we don't intend to
make anyone uncomfortable.
You say you don't
intend to, but you do.
And Osman...
... Osman is always in trouble.
First, he lost his blood brother,
then he stabbed my brother because of you.
Now he spilled his own blood.
Get your hands off Osman.
You share the same blood,
you grew up together...
... but you haven't been
able to know Osman, Hatun.
Osman is not a valiant that
can be held, or be pushed away.
Whatever he's done, he's done
with his own courage, own will.
You clearly came here filled with anger,
you don't speak about good, but only bad.
If you don't have anything
else to say, leave me alone.
I have said what I needed to say. Now, take the
curse you brought with yourselves, and begone!
I've looked everywhere in the Tent,
my Bey, neither Edebali or Bala Hatun is here.
- Tursun.
- I've also checked medics, Tursun is gone too.
Send word to the Valiants, they should
prepare, we are going to the New Bazaar.
I've brought you a meal.
Thank you Aygül Hatun,
I need to go quickly.
Are you going after that Hatun?
I would want to know why
did they leave without a word.
Don't go, Osman.
You went after her for once,
and we were drowned in troubles.
- What are you saying, Aygül Hatun?
- That Hatun is cursed.
She won't be good for you.
Everything that happened
to us is because of her.
Everything that happened to us is because of
your father and your brother's arrogance, Aygül Hatun.
You should know it like this.
Wait for me here.
Edebali.
I've never seen my Bey like this before.
When he couldn't see Edebalı and Tursun
in the Tent, Osman Bey lost himself.
- Not because of this.
- Then why?
Osman Bey lost himself when
he couldn't find Bala Hatun.
I know.
This is love.
Osman Bey's heart is
burning with love's fire.
Samsa Bey...
... what do you know about love?
Haven't you found love
in battles, in fighting?
Weren't you married with
your weapon, Sergeant Samsa?
What happened, your eyes look cloudy,
your heart is darkened, tell us?
What makes you wander
into the emptiness, my Bey?
Don't rip my heart,
or I will rip your corpses.
Sergeant Samsa, we are
brothers-in-arms with you now.
Didn't we go to the
infidel's place together?
Didn't we spill infidel's
blood together?
There are no secrets between
us from now on, tell us.
I am worried about Osman Bey.
Why is that, Samsa Bey?
Love, Boran Alp, blinds Beyhood
of Beys, blunts weapons of the valiants.
How do you know that?
Have your heart burnt with
love's fire before, Sergeant Samsa?
Burning would be too easy.
Then tell us, we are your brothers.
Mind your own business!
Please contact us for any inquiries
turkision@gmail.com